const GeneralAdministartion = [
	{
		questionText: 'Powers of రాజ్యప్రతినిధులు/రాజకుమారులు',
		ans: ['can issue new coins', 'can remove tax', 'can levy tax'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'How many Rajyalu during Acchuta Ralayas time',
		ans: ['17'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Powers of పరుపత్యం గార్లు',
		ans: ['Tax collection', 'can leavy  tax'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Tax on Enam Land of Brhammins',
		ans: ['1/6th'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Which sources tells about Tax system during Vijayanagra Kingdom',
		ans: ['శ్రీ రంగపట్టణ తామ్ర Ins', 'పరాశర మధువీయం'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'which Ins tells that గురువరాజు harresed womens for not paying taxes',
		ans: ['మాచుపల్లి కైఫియాత్'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Vijayanagras FY starts on?',
		ans: ['Maha Navami'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Avg tax collected in గుణాచారి Tax',
		ans: ['12,000 పనలు'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Famous place of Dimonds, నూలు, పట్టు, జారి',
		ans: ['Vazrakapur, Anathapur', 'Tadipatri, Adoni, Gutti,vinukonda', 'Gutti, Rayadurgam, kanchi', 'Venkatagiri'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Dyes were exportesd to?',
		ans: ['Malakka, sumitra, pegu'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Trade is mostly with ',
		ans: ['Portugeous & Arabs'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Main port, Main Port@East, Main port@West ',
		ans: ['Calicut', 'Machilipatnam', 'Batkal'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'మోట్టుపల్లి ధర్మం Ins వేయించింది ఎవరు?',
		ans: ['D.V-II after occupying from Kondavedu Reddys'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Major Exports',
		ans: ['కలంకారి వస్త్రాలు, రత్న కంబర్లు(Gem stones), దంతాలు, Perfume, Dimonds,sugar'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Major Imports',
		ans: ['Horshes, కర్పూరం, ముత్యాలు, Mercury'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Famous Trade Union',
		ans: ['Ayya vali chalu mula Trade Union', 'Chairman: Shetty Pattna Shetty'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Lipi on Coins?',
		ans: ['Devnagari lipi'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'How coins looks like?',
		ans: ['One side has ---> Hindu God + Animal', 'Anaother side ---> King name, Title'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Which king order to pay tax in the form of Coins',
		ans: ['Hari Hara Raya (mentioned in పరాశర మాధవీయం)'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Large sized Gold Coins are',
		ans: ['గద్యానం,వరాహ'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Small size gold coin',
		ans: ['pratapa/మాడ, పనం, చిన్నం'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Silver coins',
		ans: ['Thar, Maan, pesado'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Pareto',
		ans: ['Silver + copper Alloy'],
	},
	{
		questionText: '1 గద్యానం/వరాహ = ____ Pratapa',
		ans: ['2'],
	},
	{
		questionText: '1 Parata = _____ పనం',
		ans: ['10'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Which Indian Historian tells about Miliatary Administartation in Vijay',
		ans: ['నీలకంఠ శాస్త్రి'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Two types of Military system?',
		ans: ['కైజీత/సిద్ధ సైన్యం', 'Amara Nayankar sytem'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Canons were 1st used by',
		ans: ['Bukak Raya -I'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Who mention S.K.D hellps portugeus to concur Goa',
		ans: ['Father Heraas'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'S.K.D navel commender',
		ans: ['తిమ్మోజు'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'విజయనగర కాలంలో రాయబారుల సమావేశాలను పేర్కొన్నది',
		ans: ['రాయవాచకం'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Ex of సూర్యవంశం క్షత్రియులు, చంద్రవంశ క్షత్రియులు',
		ans: ['సూర్యవంశం క్షత్రియులు: Cholas, Gajapathi', 'చంద్రవంశ క్షత్రియులు: Pandyas, Vijayanagara'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Main Sports',
		ans: ['మల్ల యుద్దం, Chess, Horse Riding'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Major Festivals',
		ans: ['Dasara, Holi'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Entertainment',
		ans: ['Hunting, Music & Dange'],
	},
	{
		questionText: '',
		ans: [''],
	},
	{
		questionText: '',
		ans: [''],
	},
	{
		questionText: '',
		ans: [''],
	},

];

export default GeneralAdministartion;
